<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the Generall Assemblie of the confederate Catholiques of Ireland the ensuing declaration of the Lord Nuncio, &amp; his partie of the clergie, we thinke fit to be printed and published, to the end that all men may see and abhorre the malice &amp; irregularity of those that subscribed that instrument ... whereof there hath been a sad example already in the towne of Gallway.</title>
            <author>Ireland. General Assembly at Kilkenny.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B24693</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">19347537</idno>
  <idno type="VID">205511</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240886623</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing I393A</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">19347537</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B24693)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 205511)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1673:17)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the Generall Assemblie of the confederate Catholiques of Ireland the ensuing declaration of the Lord Nuncio, &amp; his partie of the clergie, we thinke fit to be printed and published, to the end that all men may see and abhorre the malice &amp; irregularity of those that subscribed that instrument ... whereof there hath been a sad example already in the towne of Gallway.</title>
                  <author>Ireland. General Assembly at Kilkenny.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 broadside.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>By command of the Generall Assembly ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Printed at Kilkenny :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1648.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imperfect: creased and tightly bound with some loss of print.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="corporate_name">Catholic Church --  Ireland --  History --  17th century.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Ireland --  History --  1625-1649.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="declaration">
            <pb facs="tcp:205511:1"/>
            <head>BY THE GENERALL ASSEMBLIE OF THE CONFEDERATE CATHOLIQVES OF IRELAND.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>He ensuing Declaration of the Lord Nuncio, &amp; his partie of the Clergie, We thinke fit to be printed and published, to the end that all men may see and abhorre the malice &amp; irregularity of those that subscribed that Instrument, thereby disswading the people, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nder the specious pretence of Conscience from their allegiance to his Maiestie, and due obedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nce to the Civill Magistrat, and inviting them to breach of publick Faith, Rapines, Murther, &amp; <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>lood-shed; whereof there hath been a sad example already in the Towne of <hi>Gallway,</hi> where (by <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he countenance of that bloody instrument soone after the publishing thereof) the Magistrats <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ouse was violently assaulted, and the Kings sword, the keyes of the Towne-gates, and other en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>gnes of Office forcibly taken thereout, by a rout of people lead by one of the Subscribers of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he Instrument, and brought into the Church, which occasioned such a tumult, as some blood as drawne, one man kill'd, and many lives were endangered, till for the appeasing thereof; the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ord Nuncio seeing that partie overpowr'd by a number of others loyall and well affected to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he Government, went to the Church, and thereout in person brought, and restored the said <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>word, Keyes, and Enseignes to the Mayor in his house; And least it may worke the like, or worse <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ffects in any other place, or with any other persons. It is this day unanimously declared by <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>his Assembly, that the said Declaration or Instrument is in it selfe wicked, malicious and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>raiterous, repugnant to all lawes, Human and Divine, and tending to the utter subversion of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he Government of the Church, and Commonwealth of this Kingdome; the Subscribers endea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vouring to engage the Confederat Catholiques, in an irreconciliable rent and division, which will more evidently appeare by other Acts and Declarations of this Assembly, ready to be pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>blished; which Instrument followeth.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Richard Blake, Prol. Gen. Conv.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="declaration">
            <head>In the Name of God, Amen.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Here<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> about our late decision touching the Proclamation of the Cessation, it was ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>iected by some, that though for the losse of some temporall goods, they might not se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>curely in Conscience, proclaime the said Cessation: yet the doubt they have made was, of the lo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>e of mens lives, which may ensue the opposing of it, Wee doe hereby declare, that it is <hi>a dead<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>y sinne against the Law of God, and his Church,</hi> and <hi>a periurie against the Oath of Association,</hi> to have or to suffer the said <hi>Cessation</hi> to be proclaimed; and therefore they are obliged to loos<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> both lives, goods, liberties, and all that is deere to them in the world, rather then to obey or pro<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>laime it; This was the sense likewise of those words in our former decree. <hi>It is in no wise lawfull, &amp;c.</hi> And truely we knew full well, that they could not loose their goods in this Quarrell, without the losse of some lives, or many lives perhaps.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Witnesse our hands, <date>the thir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tieth day of <hi>August,</hi> 1648.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>Signed,
<list>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Joannes Baptiste Archiepiscopus</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Firmanus Nuncius Apostolicus.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Ioannes Rapotensis.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Fr. Boëtius Rossensis.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Walterus Clonfertensis.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Robertus Corcagiensis &amp; Cloan.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Fr. Terentius I<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="2 letters">
                              <desc>••</desc>
                           </gap>olacensis.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Fr. Athon. Episcopus Clonmacnois.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Fr. Dionisus ô Driscoll. Provincialis Augustinorum.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Patricius Lynch Praepositus.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Fr. Gregorius French.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Fr. Bernarlus Connius.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Stephanus Lynch Doctor.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Nicholaus Condulmanus.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Iames Fallan V. A. A.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Iacobus Abbas de Conge.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Gregorius Joyce.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Michael Lynch.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed at Kilkenny, by command of the Generall Assembly, in the yeare of our Lord God, <hi>1648. Phill. Kearney Cler. Gen. Conv.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>